DARIAN YANF

PROFILE

Data Analyst, Python Developer, MBA and Bachelor's Degree in **Economics**

Data and business analyst with more than 20 years of experience in the banking, pharmaceutical, power generation, investment and technological transformation industries.

Analytical, organized, and highly resolutive profile.

Training and experience in various areas and industries, allow me to have a deep analysis of business needs, providing added value beyond data analysis.

D. Hb a.a

SKILLS

SQL	Python	Power BI
Tableau	Looker	Excel (with Macros)
BigQuery	Pandas	Power Query
DAX	Numpy	R
Attention to detail	Research	Problem-solving skills
Django	API	Communication
GIT	Matplotlib	Presentations
CSS	Logic	Investments
Economy	Finance	Mathematics
Business		0
D03111033	Statistics	Collaboration

Dower DI

CONTACT

🖍 Mar del Plata, Argentina



(+54) 11-5311-7020



yanedarian.dev@gmail.com



darianyane.com



github.com/DarianYane



linkedin.com/in/darian-yane/

EDUCATION

GOOGLE DATA ANALYTICS PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE,

COURSERA, 2023

PYTHON, CODERHOUSE, 2022

MASTER IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION (MBA), UADE, 2020

Distinction: MAGNA LAUDE

Average: 8.68 (2nd best course average)

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN ECONOMICS, UBA, 2011

ECONOMIC ACTUARY, (abandoned, 27 subjects approved)

WORK EXPERIENCE

CORPORATE DEVELOPMENT AND TRANSACTION SERVICES (CDTS) **SPECIALIST**, ACCENTURE

04/2023 - present

• Deal Shaping and Pricing (Costing and Valuation of New Businesses).

PYTHON TUTOR, CODERHOUSE

12/2022 - 03/2023

INVESTMENT ANALYST/EDITOR, INVERSOR GLOBAL

09/2021 - 01/2023

FREELANCER (EXCEL), FIVERR

01-2021 - 09/2021

• I made all kinds of Excels on request, which included pivot tables, macros, filters, dynamic drop-downs, etc.

DATA ANALYST, AES SERVICIOS AMÉRICA

09/2019 - 08/2020

- Collect, cleanse, analyze, reconcile, and visualize data from different sources.
- Assist the business in the face of problems that require data-based solutions.
- Generation of monthly reports.
- KPI tracking.
- Projections of the different variables of the sector.

Achievements

- Created KPI reports using SAP, Excel, Power Query and Power BI.
- Automated tax payment processes using macros in Excel. Reduced the probability of erroneous payments to 0% and standardized the processing time, achieving a 70% reduction.
- Established Dashboards for each of the Accounts Payable countries.

You can see the rest of my professional experience in linkedin.com/in/darian-yane/

- <u>1st Place Tournament "ACBSP Company</u> Game", Company Game, 2019
- Member of the Argentine <u>Team that participated in the 9th</u>
 <u>Southern Cone</u> Olympiad, Argentine Mathematical Olympiad (OMA), 1998
- <u>National Mention in the 13th Argentine Mathematical</u>
 <u>Olympiad</u>, Argentine Mathematical Olympiad (OMA), 1996

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH, Advanced
PORTUGUESE, Advanced
SPANISH, Native